<pkmkdoc spec="1.12"><properties><title>PostgreSQL for Mac</title><build>/Volumes/KINGSTON/PostgreSQL for Mac.mpkg</build><organization>com.druware.postgresqlformac</organization><userSees ui="both"/><min-target os="2"/><domain system="true"/></properties><distribution><versions min-spec="1.000000"/><scripts></scripts></distribution><description>Installs a full PostgreSQL Database server environment on Mac OS X.</description><contents><choice title="Database Server" id="choice0" description="The core of the PostgreSQL for Mac deployment, this is the PostgreSQL Database engine, packaged and installed to the /Library/PostgreSQL location." starts_selected="true" starts_enabled="false" starts_hidden="false"><pkgref id="com.druware.postgresqlformac.postgresqlForMac.postgresql8.pkg"/><pkgref id="com.druware.postgresqlformac.postgresqlForMac.postgresqlServer.pkg"/><choice title="StartUp Item" id="choice1" starts_selected="true" starts_enabled="false" starts_hidden="false"><pkgref id="com.druware.postgresqlformac.postgresqlForMac.postgresql.pkg"/></choice><choice title="Server Applications" id="choice5" starts_selected="true" starts_enabled="true" starts_hidden="false"><pkgref id="com.druware.postgresqlformac.postgresqlForMac.queryToolForPostgres.pkg"/><pkgref id="com.druware.postgresqlformac.postgresqlForMac.createDatabase.pkg"/><pkgref id="com.druware.postgresqlformac.postgresqlForMac.createUser.pkg"/></choice></choice><choice title="Database Access Toolkits" id="choice3" starts_selected="true" starts_enabled="true" starts_hidden="false"><choice title="Java (JDBC3)" id="choice6" description="Recommended JDBC Driver for Java 1.5." starts_selected="true" starts_enabled="true" starts_hidden="false"><pkgref id="com.druware.postgresqlformac.postgresqlForMac.postgresql83603jdbc3.pkg"/></choice><choice title="PGSQLKit Framework" id="choice11" description="PGSQLKit Framework for development and deployment of linked applications " starts_selected="true" starts_enabled="true" starts_hidden="false"><pkgref id="com.druware.postgresqlformac.postgresqlForMac.pgsqlkit.pkg"/></choice></choice></contents><resources bg-scale="tofit" bg-align="bottomleft"><locale lang="en"><resource relative="true" type="background">../PostgreSQL/Resources/background.tif</resource><resource mime-type="text/rtf" kind="embedded" type="license"><![CDATA[{\rtf1\ansi\ansicpg1252\cocoartf949\cocoasubrtf350
{\fonttbl\f0\fnil\fcharset0 Verdana;\f1\fmodern\fcharset0 Courier;}
{\colortbl;\red255\green255\blue255;}
\pard\tx560\tx1120\tx1680\tx2240\tx2800\tx3360\tx3920\tx4480\tx5040\tx5600\tx6160\tx6720\ql\qnatural

\f0\fs26 \cf0 All portions of this installation fall under the BSD license with the exception of the PostgreSQL ODBC driver.  That exception is under a Gnu GPL of LGPL license. Copies of all three licenses are installed with their respective packages.\
\
The BSD license, means that in the simplest terms is that  you can do whatever you want with the product and source code as long  as you don't claim you wrote it or sue us. You should give it a read though, it's only half a page and follows below:\
\

\f1 Portions Copyright (c) 1997-2008, PostgreSQL Global Development Group\
All rights reserved.\
\
Portions Copyright (c) 2004-2008, Druware Software Designs\
All rights reserved.\
\
Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met:\
\
1. Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer. \
2. Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution. \
3. Neither the name of the PostgreSQL Global Development Group nor the names of its contributors may be used to endorse or promote products derived from this software without specific prior written permission.\
\
THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS "AS IS" AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT OWNER OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.\
}]]></resource><resource mime-type="text/rtf" kind="embedded" type="readme"><![CDATA[{\rtf1\ansi\ansicpg1252\cocoartf949\cocoasubrtf350
{\fonttbl\f0\fnil\fcharset0 LucidaGrande;}
{\colortbl;\red255\green255\blue255;\red102\green102\blue102;}
\pard\tx720\tx1440\tx2160\tx2880\tx3600\tx4320\tx5040\tx5760\tx6480\tx7200\tx7920\tx8640\ql\qnatural

\f0\fs24 \cf0 This distribution contains code from several sources, and while the bulk of the projects are released under BSD style licenses, pgsqlODBC, the ODBC driver is a Gnu Public License project, and uses either the GPL of LGPL, so it is safe to build closed source applications that dynamically link against it. \
\
The core of the PostgreSQL database engine is from http://www.postgresql.org, and is \cf2  Copyright \'a9 1996 \'96 2008 PostgreSQL Global Development Group\cf0 . \
\
The JDBC driver is from http://jdbc.postgresql.org/index.html and is also  \cf2  Copyright \'a9 1996 \'96 2008 PostgreSQL Global Development Group\cf0 .   \
\
The ODBC driver is from http://odbc.postgresql.org/ and is also \cf2 Copyright \'a9 1996 \'96 2008 PostgreSQL Global Development Group\cf0 , with other credits to the original developers, and later updates and changes from Insight Systems.\
\
The various graphical tools for Mac OS X are \cf2 Copyright \'a9 2004 \'96 2008 Druware Software Designs\cf0 .\
\
The StartupItem is slightly modified from the one that Marc Liyange created, along with his original efforts at getting PostgreSQL running on Mac OS X.}]]></resource><resource mime-type="text/rtf" kind="embedded" type="welcome"><![CDATA[{\rtf1\ansi\ansicpg1252\cocoartf949\cocoasubrtf350
{\fonttbl\f0\fnil\fcharset0 LucidaGrande;}
{\colortbl;\red255\green255\blue255;\red128\green0\blue0;}
\pard\tx720\tx1440\tx2160\tx2880\tx3600\tx4320\tx5040\tx5760\tx6480\tx7200\tx7920\tx8640\ql\qnatural

\f0\fs24 \cf0 Welcome to the PostgreSQL for Mac OS X unified installer.  This installer is intended to install the PostgreSQL Database server along with most of the needed tools to make it ready to use and easy to administer out of the box.\
\
In the next few steps, you will be given the option to customize which items you wish to install.  For most users, the default options should be sufficient, however, that may not be the case for all users.  The default installation includes many data access methods, and the graphical administration tools.  \
\
\pard\tx720\tx1440\tx2160\tx2880\tx3600\tx4320\tx5040\tx5760\tx6480\tx7200\tx7920\tx8640\ql\qnatural
\cf2 If you are upgrading from a previous version, you 
\b must
\b0  shut down the running copy, and it is strongly recommended that you take a few moments to make a full backup of your databases before you upgrade.\cf0 \
\
Thank you for choosing PostgreSQL.}]]></resource></locale></resources><flags/><item type="file">01postgresql.xml</item><item type="file">02postgresql.xml</item><item type="file">03postgresql.xml</item><item type="file">04pgsqlkit.xml</item><item type="file">05query.xml</item><item type="file">06create.xml</item><item type="file">07create.xml</item><item type="file">08postgresql.xml</item><mod>properties.customizeOption</mod><mod>properties.title</mod><mod>description</mod><mod>properties.systemDomain</mod><mod>properties.anywhereDomain</mod></pkmkdoc>